<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RIZVI</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="long_text">Press the download button to see the complete document.</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="Collaborations_title">MOUs / Collaborations with Institutions / Other universities / Industries / Corporate Entities:-</string>
    <string name="Collaborations">>> LOU with Bhartiya Vidyapeeth University IMED, Pune for Faculty Exchange Programme and Research Activities.\n\n>> MOU - Visara Technologies Services LLP for GROW YOUR SKILL learning program for Final year students. Number of students registered 34.(2016-17)\n\n>> “CREEDY” employability program conducted by Techno serve in collaboration with Citibank’s CSR initiative and British Council on “Skill Set Enhancement and Employability support for Youth in Urban Slums in Mumbai”. This 100 hrs program is free of cost. A Certificate on successful completion of Course was provided.\n\n>> MOU was signed with AIM Institute of Management for short term courses under skill development program for one year diploma course in Marketing Management/Business Management/Dip in Accountancy and Book keeping Courses for Minority students only (127 students enrolled). Also around 80 students registered for Certificate course in Travel and Tourism. This course was also free of cost with scholarship of Rs 1450/- awarded upon completion of the course (2015-16).\n\n>> TOI India (CSR Initiative) in collaboration with British Council tied up with Institute for imparting free short term courses in Communication And Soft Skill development program. (2016-17)\n\n>> NSS unit signed an MOU with Anubhav Mumbai which is a non-profit or ganisation with a mission to work for Underprivileged, Youth and Women.\n\n>> NSS unit of the College undertake Mega Medical Camp in collaboration with Lions Club of Oshiwara and Think Foundation every year.\n\n>> NSS collaborated with TATA Memorial Hospital for Blood Donation.\n\n>> NSS also collaborated with Zahan Foundation for holding Medical Camp for Teaching and Non – Teaching Staff of the college.\n\n>> NSS Unit and Environment Committee collaborated with Stree Mukti Sanghatana (NGO) on Paper Recycling, E - Waste, Compost Pit and Green Audit.\n\n>> WDC Department collaborated with Akshara, Population first and Ladli to organise various competitions, seminars and workshops on Gender Issues.</string>
    <string name="dpbotsetailstxt">he course structure, eligibility and selection criteria is as per University of Mumbai norms. The coaching for course work and the doctoral thesis work is done at the Institute under the able guidance of the Ph.D. guide Dr. Nitesh Joshi. The Institute offers excellent research facilities in terms of statistical packages, online databases, online journals, etc. \n\nThe current details of the Ph.D. program are as given below</string>
    <string name="Convocation_details">1) Convocation Ceremony 2020 on 29th February 2020 at 8:30 a.m\n\n2) Registration will be considered only after payment of fees at the office fees counter\n\n3) Registration Fees: Rs. 500/- (Rs. 400/- for Convocation and 100/- for Alumni registration) to be paid in cash at the Admin Office fees counter on the ground floor from 10:30 a.m. to 1:00 p.m. and 2:00 p.m. to 4:30 p.m.\n\n4) Please show the confirmation mail that you receive after filling the form, at the fees counter and pay the fees\n\n5) Please check your name in the list before Registration\n\n6) Last Date for Registration - 27th February, 2020\n\n7) Names of B.Sc.I.T. and B.Sc.C.S. students can be found in B.Sc. list\n\n8) Names of B.B.I. and B.A.F. students can be found in B.Com list\n\n9) Registration form link is given below</string>
    <string name="ncc_1string">N.C.C cadets of Rizvi College have regularlyand successfully participated in Physically and mentally highly demanding national level camps (competitions) like TSC (ThalSena Camp), RDC (Republic Day Camp) etc. Though this in itself an achievement, someendured to achieved greater goals.</string>
    <string name="ncc_2string">Sushant Sail, a second year cadet of Rizvi college was the sole cadet from Mumbai selected to Maharashtra Kabbaddi team in N.C.C National Games, Delhi in August 2015. The Maharashtra team won silver medal in the competition.</string>
    <string name="Ncc_title_string">Individual Achievements of N.C.C Cadets (June 2015 - August 2016)</string>
    <string name="ncc_3string">TusharTavandkar, a third year cadet and S.Y.B.COM student of Rizvi College, competed with the cadets of 01.Maharashtra.Battalion and won gold medal in obstacle race at ThalSena Camp (TSC), Nashik in July 2016. He was selected through thetraining and elimination rounds of the first three camps of the series of back to back camps (each of 12 days duration) that leads to prestigious national level competition in Delhi in the September, 2016.</string>
    <string name="ncc_4string">Khan Kaif, a second year cadet and S.Y.J.C. science student of Rizvi College, at the time of writing this article, has already made it through the training and elimination rounds of the first five camps and is currently being trained in the sixth camp of the series of camps that cumulates to competing in the prestigious national level competition in Delhi in September, 2016.</string>
    <string name="Assocation">\n> WOMEN’S DEVELOPMENT CELL: It is a special cell to inculcate self-reliance, boldness and confidence in girl students, so that, they can march shoulder to shoulder with their male counter parts.
\n\n> DLLE: The Department of Lifelong Learning and Extension has been recognized as a department to promote meaningful and sustained rapport between colleges and communities.
\n\n> ALUMNI ASSOCIATION: The ex-student Association has been set up to provide a platform for mutual inter-face among the past and present students of the college. To utilize the expertise and experiences of the ex-students for the upliftment of the performance of the College and to guide the present students to achieve their goals in a better way.
\n\n> NATIONAL CADET CORPS (NCC): The College has been allowed to raise a NCC unit for boys attached to the 01 st Maharashtra Battalion NCC Army Wing. It has a strength of One Part-Time Commissioned Officer and 60 Cadets. The NCC training imparted to the cadets during regular parades which are held on Sundays and in the various camps held during the year. The Cadets are prepared for the "B" and "C" certificate examinations. Students who desire to enroll for the NCC should contact the NCC officer.
\n\n> NATIONAL SOCIAL SERVICE (NSS):To encourage students to play a larger and more active role in the society, the college provides the NSS scheme at both the Degree and Junior College level. Students who desire to join the scheme should contact the NSS officer. This extra• institutional service is available free-of-charge to the students.
\n\n> STUDENT’S GRIEVANCE CELL:It has been set up to create a harmonious environment by redressing the grievances of the students concerned with academic and other related matters.
\n\n> CAREER GUIDANCE AND PLACEMENT CELL: It provides an opportunity to students to seek new openings after completing their College education and help them in moulding their career and placement.
\n\n> STUDENT’S COUNSELING CELL:Counseling is done by professionals who look after the welfare of the students by helping them to cope with stress and developing confidence among them to overcome and face highs and lows of the life.
\n\n> STUDENT’S1 COUNCIL:It consists of student representatives who look after and promote the productive involvement of the students in the day to day activities of the college.
\n\n> Mahila Takrar Nivaran Samiti This cell was constituted by State Government, and made mandatory in all organizations, public as well as private sector, when there was a demanding need to protect women folk against crime done to them in work-place.</string>
    <string name="ncc_string5">Care-taker office of N.C.C Unit, Rizvi College, would like to thank respected Principal, Dr. M. Z. Farooqui and Vice-Principal,Dr.AnjumAra for supporting and encouraging N.C.C, Ex. A.N.O Ashok Singh for guidance post retirement from N.C.C.\n\nAll the efforts, support, encouragement and guidance put in by the college will eventually be of no significance without the spirited, diligent and persistent efforts put in by the cadets of our N.C.C. unit. They rightfully deserve the greatest appreciation.\n\nThank You.</string>
    <string name="research_center_details">The institute has Approved Research centres for the below given Four Subjects, fully equipped with the necessary laboratory and infrastructural facilities</string>
    <string name="avishkar_string1">Avishkar Research Convention was constituted for the academic year 2016-17 with Dr (Mrs.) Anjum Ara Ahmad, as the Convenor and Mrs Mariyah Ghor, Mr Vishwas Deshmukh, Mr Sameer Charania and Dr. Alkama Faqih as members.</string>
    <string name="avishkar_string2"><![CDATA[>To promote, train and mentor students for research.\n\n> To conduct orientation programs to orient students towards research.\n\n> To invite experts from other colleges to train and guide the student.\n\n> To conduct training sessions so as to prepare them to present research proposals.\n\n> To organize intra collegiate research competition.\n\n> To motivate and train students to take part in Avishkar Research Convention at the University level.]]></string>
    <string name="Iqac_string1"><![CDATA[> The department of IQAC has organised a Faculty development programme (FDP) on Use of various technology tools and technology for handling new curriculum addressed by Mr Mandar Bhanushe, Assitant Professor cum Assitant Director, IDOL, University of Mumbai on 2nd July 2016 in Seminar room. About 30 faculties attended the program. \n\n> The department of IQAC has organised a Faculty development programme (FDP) on Use of Online Resources for teaching learning development and use addressed by Mr Santosh C Hulagabali, Librarian, Nagindas Khandwala College, Mumbai on 14th July 2016 in Seminar room. About 30 faculties attended the program. \n\n> The department of IQAC has organised a two day Faculty development programme (FDP) on Internal Auditors Training Program addressed by Mr Madhav Dewoolkaris, Senior Quality Auditor registered with UK based IRCA for ISO and TQM, GMP, HACCP, PPE, BRC and EMS & Mrs. Aparna Thakkar an expert from the field of Environment, Laboratory and Quality Assessment related services on 9th and 23rd July 2016 in Seminar room. 27 teaching and non teaching staff attended the internal auditors training program and about 15 staff successfully passed the internal auditors training program and are now certified auditors as per ISO 9001:2008 standard. \n\n> The department of IQAC has organised an orientation programme on Recent Changes in NAAC addressed by Mr. Waheedul Hasan, Publishing Department NAAC, Bangalore on 13th October 2016 at 11.30 am in Seminar room. \n\n>Dr (Mrs) Anjum Ara Ahmad, \nVice-Principal, Coordinator IQAC]]></string>
    <string name="Iqac_string2"><![CDATA[>The IQAC cell of Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce is a very active cell. The main purpose of the cell is to assure quality in higher education. In order to achieve its purpose the cell keeps on organising many activities through the year. Some of the major initiatives take by IQAC in the year 2013-16 are as follows:- \n\n 1. Talk by an Expert:- Organised talk by an expert Dr. Sarode to brief how to send proposal for Major And Minor Research as well as how to write research papers. \n\n 2. International Research Journal of the College:- In an endeavour to promote research a peer reviewed bi-annual research journal International Journal of Research was started in 2011 by the college by including eminent researchers and academicians on the editorial board. Several members of our teaching staff and throughout the nation and abroad have been contributing regularly to this journal of repute. The journal has completed five years. The abstract of the papers has been uploaded on the Google scholar. \n\n 3. State level Seminar:- A State level Seminar on Quality Enhancement in Higher Education through NAAC Accreditation on 14th August 2014 \n\n 4. State Level Workshop for Non-teaching Staff:- A State level Workshop on Maintenance and Repairing of laboratory equipments for the Laboratory Assistants And Laboratory Attendants from 2nd to 7th February 2015 in collaboration with Western Regional Instrumentation Centre (WRIC), Mumbai was organised by NSS, IQAC and Dept of Sciences. \n\n 5. Computer literacy training for teachers:- A five day workshop for Computer learning was organised by the IQAC in coordination with the CS And IT Department for all the teachers of the degree college from 9th to 13th February 2015. \n\n 6. Workshop on Research:- A workshop was organised on “Techniques for writing research papers, articles and Ph.D. Proposal” on 11th December 2015. \n\n 7. Academic Audit:- The year started with the visit of the Academic Audit team from University of Mumbai on 18th June 2015. A team consisting of one former Vice Chancellor Dr Vijay Padharipande, Mumbai Univ IQAC Director Dr Madhukar and one Principal Dr B S Birajdar. The team went through the presentations of all Departments and a few committees. The committee submitted its report which highlighted some good comments and a few recommendations to fulfil. \n\n 8. API Workshop:- A one day workshop on API for College Teachers was organized by the University of Mumbai in Association with Internal Quality Assurance Cell of Rizvi College of A/S/C, DTSS College of Commerce, J M Patel College of Commerce and Narsee Monjee College of Commerce And Economics. This workshop was organized in Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce on 29th August 2015 with IQAC of Rizvi College taking the leading role. The workshop got an overwhelming response despite of being a holiday in most colleges due to Raksha Bandan. Teachers from all over the State from as far as Ratnagiri attended the workshop. More than one hundred and twenty five teachers and IQAC coordinators attended the workshop which included seventeen teachers from our college. \n\n 9. ISO 9001: 2008 certification:- The College was also ISO 9001:2008 certified this year. The internal audit was on 10th December 2015 and the external audit was conducted on 14th December 2015 and finally in the exit meeting on the same day the external auditor gave the final Nod for the certification of the college. Dr (Mrs) Anjum Ara Ahmad the Vice-Principal of the College was appointed the Management Representative for the same. \n\n 10. Training to Office Staff:- A ten day training programme sponsored by IQAC was organised for Non- teaching staff for Accounting Package Tally and Excel from 15th October to 30th October 2015 in our Computer Lab. At the end of the course the staffs had to give exam and were given certificates for the same. Students were also trained at a nominal fee. The training was given by Font Computers. This program was conducted in coordination with the Dept of Commerce and Dept of Computer Sceince. \n\n 11. E-Learning:- Training for Students mainly from Commerce faculty was organised on 19th November 2015 on E-learning Programme for all subjects, CPT and other Competitive exam. This training programme was conducted in coordination with Goyal Academy (Gold). \n\n 12. PAN Card:- To create awareness towards paying proper taxes to the government and make students and staff abide by it. Arrangements to issue PAN Cards at Special PAN Camp were made between 10th February 2015 and 12th February 2015 in coordination with Infrastructure Technology and Services ( a Govt. Of India Company) at a very nominal rate. Sixty two applications were collected during this period. \n\n 13. Seminar on NAAC Accreditation:- To train Teaching and Non-teaching staff a Seminar was organised in the college on 01st July 2015entitled “Quality Improvement through for NAAC Accreditation” in the Seminar Room where 105 teaching and non teaching staff attended the same. Dr Dharmadhikari N.S., Former Principal, a member of NAAC (Bangalore) Peer team from Pune was the resource person. \n\n 14. Workshop on Quality Enhancement:- A one day workshop was organised on 14th July 2015 for teaching staff entitled “Accreditation Process and Quality Enhancement in Higher Education”. Dr Vijay M Pandharipandey, a Former VC of Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada University, Aurangabad was the resource person \n\n 15. Workshop on Examination Rules:- A workshop was jointly organised by JM Patel College and Rizvi College of Arts, Science and Commerce on “SIMPLIFYING EXAMINATION RULES” on 10th October, 2015 at JM Patel College, Goregaon. Academic Year 2014-15 faced significant modifications in the Examination System employed by the University of Mumbai. Some of the changes are introduction of CBSGS System in 2013-14, scaling down of internal marks, changes in ATKT system etc. 76 took part in the workshop coming from various Colleges affiliated to University of Mumbai. Panel consisted of Shri. Sunil B. Mantri, Dr. M. Z. Farooqui, Dr. Debajit N. Sarkar and Shri. Madhav Rao. Shri. Sunil B. Mantri concentrated on objective of the introduction of CBSGS system. This system introduced 7 point grades, but failed to differentiate the grade between students who scored 70% and 90%. To be more precise, both students scoring 70% and 90% get ‘O’ Grade was highlighted. Dr. M. Z. Farooqui focused on CGPA calculation and its disadvantages. Shri. Madhav Rao focused on changes that could be beneficial for learners. \n\n 16. Workshop for IQAC Members:- A workshop on “ Enriching SSR” was jointly organised by Smt. Kapila Khandvala College of Education, L S Raheja College of Arts and Commerce, Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce, J M Patel College of Commerce in Smt. Kapila Khandvala College of Education on 2nd April 2016. The resource person was Dr Shirish Chindhade, Former Principal and a Trained Assessor of NAAC Peer Team. About thirty faculties attended the said workshop which included eight of our IQAC Members. \n\n 17. Study Centre of Jamia Milia Islamia:- A tie-up was activated with prestigious institute Jamia Milia Islamia, New Delhi, a Central University for being the study centre of Distance Mode programme for MA(except Education And HRM), MCom, BA, BBA, BCom, BCom(IBF), CCHNI, CCIT.]]></string>
    <string name="Iqac_string3"><![CDATA[>18. Tie-up with MIT, New Zealand:- Founded in 1970, Manukau Institute of Technology(MIT) is one of New Zealand’s largest and most prestigious government Institutes of Technology with 16,000 students enrolled per annum and over 1,000 international students studying business, information technology, engineering, maritime and culinary programs. Estero New Zealand Limited played an instrumental role in identifying the opportunity and getting two highly reputed institutions from India (Rizvi College of Arts Science and Commerce) and New Zealand (Manukau Institute of Technology) to join hands and provide students the opportunity to study through a collaborative learning environment. The collaboration between the two institutions makes international education more accessible and affordable for the students. The MoU was signed by Secretary Rizvi Education Society, Mr. Abis Rizvi (Extreme left in Photograph), Dean of Management Studies MIT, New Zealand Dr John (Extreme right in Photograph) and Mr Kshitij Garg ( In centre) of ESTERO, New Zealand on February 14, 2016.This collaboration also becomes the first such initiative for the state of Maharashtra. The two institutions from India and New Zealand signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) on the 23rd February 2016. This agreement will allow Indian sub-continent students to begin their degree studies in India and conclude it in New Zealand. It will give students a unique opportunity to internationalize their degree and add to the global work-force. They will be prepared well in terms of understanding New Zealand culture, New Zealand Study Methodologies, what to expect from the country etc. Apart from this they save on approx. 40% on their study cost and living cost if they had to do the complete 3-year degree from New Zealand. Not to forget, the student gains an international degree recognised around the world, alongside gaining work experience during their final semester in New Zealand. After getting a degree, students will get work permit for one and half year. Once they complete work service he will get Permanent Residence (PR) which will add wings to their careers. Five Course are introduced for the students, they are \n\n Rizvi College Bachelors of Management Studies, Bachelors of Banking and Insurance, Bachelors of Accountancy and Finance and Bachelors of Information Techology pathway to MIT Bachelor of Applied Management. (In this course there are two options 1+2 years and 1.5+1.5 years, i.e. 1 or 1.5 years in Rizvi College and remaining years in MIT, New Zealand) \n\n Rizvi College Bachelor of Mass Management Pathway to MIT Bachelor of Applied Management. (In this course for BMM students there is only one option 1+2 years). \n\n19. Collaboration with IIAI:- Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce has collaborated with Institute of ISO Auditing And Implementation (IIAI) for Business Courses in the Field of ISO for all students of Commerce/ Arts/ Science Stream And Other Streams. The purpose of the course is that the students can become a business entrepreneur or get a job in any industry at management level. Courses offered by IIAI are Diploma And Post Graduation Diploma Courses in \nISO 9001 - Quality Management System \nISO 14001 - Environment Management System \nISO 22000 - Food Safety Management System \nISO 27001 - Information Security Management System \nISO 31000 - Risk Management System \nISO 45001 - Occupational Health And Safety Management System \nISO 50001 - Energy Management System \n\n 20. Environmental awareness:- With a view to improve the environment, compost pit has been constructed which takes care of garbage disposal of the college. \n\n 21. Faculty Development Programs (FDPs) to enhance better teaching and learning:- In order to introduce the new techniques used in teaching and learning a FDP on Use of various technology tools and technology for handling new curriculum was organised by IQAC on 2nd July which was attended by thirty teachers. To introduce the various online resources another FDP was organised by IQAC on on 14th July 2016 in the Seminar Room. This training was well attended by teachers as well as students. \n\n 22. Internal Auditors Training Program:- To check at regularly intervals that our quality management systems are in place, the IQAC conducted a two day “Internal Auditors Training Program”. Mr Madhav Dewoolkaris a very Senior Quality Auditor registered with UK based IRCA for ISO and TQM, GMP, HACCP, PPE, BRC and EMS. And Mrs Aparna Thakkar an expert from the field of Environment, Laboratory and Quality Assessment related services were the resource persons. Twenty seven teaching and non teaching staff attended this program. Sixteen staff successfully qualified this training program and now are certified auditors. We can now organise internal ISO audit at regular intervals with help of these certified auditors. \n\n23. Gender Audit:- Gender Audit was conducted to identify challenges to integrate gender in the mission of societal development and provide opportunities for girl students to enhance their future. This study has helped us to identify and understand aspects hindering the overall betterment of girls and our College strives to provide an environment to help each of our students become achievers and global citizens. \n\n24. Remedial Lectures And Bridge Courses:- Remedial Lectures are arranged for the slow learners. IQAC also motivates teachers to conduct Bridge Courses for the first year students. \n\nThe above mentioned achievements would have been possible without the motivation and keen interest of Chairperson of IQAC and Principal Dr M Z Farooqui. We are also thankful to the Management for the support given by them in organising these programs. \n\nDr ( Mrs.) Anjum Ara Ahmad \nCoordinator IQAC]]></string>
    <string name="Iqac_string4"><![CDATA[>One day State Level Seminar on “Quality Enhancement in Higher Education through NAAC Accreditation Process” was organized by Internal Quality Assurance Cell (IQAC) on 14th August 2014. Dr. M Z Farooqui, Principal, Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce was the Chairperson and Dr. (Mrs.) Anjum Ara Ahmad, Vice-Principal was the Convenor of the Seminar. \n\n> Principal Dr M Z Farooqui welcomed the guest and gave the welcome speech. Dr (Mrs) Anjum Ara Ahmad, the Coordinator and Vice- Principal briefed the audience about the various activities of IQAC in Rizvi College. Dr M A Khan the Registrar of University of Mumbai, was supposed to give the Keynote Address but could not make it due to some sudden preoccupations at the University. Dr Sarkar, the Principal of J M Patel College gave the keynote address. He spoke on “Quality Enhancement in Higher Education through NAAC Accreditation Process”. He pointed out the Role of NAAC in Higher Education and spoke on the Five Main Objectives of NAAC. \n\n> The First Technical Session was taken by Dr. M R Krupe, Former Principal of Vaze College of Arts, Science And Commerce and Pioneer in NAAC Accreditation. A Detailed discussion on the Key Aspects and their weightages as per the New Manual given by NAAC was presented by him. He explained all the Key Aspects of the Seven Criterions and suggested how the IQAC should handle them. His speech was very specific, to the point and very informative. He gave the assurance to the college that they can take his guidance as and when require. \n\n> The Second Technical Session was handled by Dr Shobana Vasudevan, Principal, R A Podar College of Commerce And Economics. Her talk was based on “Importance of Self Study Report (SSR) submitted by the College in NAAC Accreditation”. She gave an extempore talk on importance of the report. She highlighted the precautions to be taken while preparing the SSR report. She also explained in detail how one should go about while making the report. \n\n> We got an overwhelming for the Seminar. More than eighty participants from all over the State attended the Seminar. The participants included mainly Vice- Principals and IQAC Coordinators. Principals of Five Colleges were also present in the audience. All participants were given Printed Notes and Handouts of the workshop]]></string>
    <string name="Iqac_string5"><![CDATA[>A one day workshop on API for College Teachers was organized by the University of Mumbai in Association with Internal Quality Assurance Cell of Rizvi College of A/S/C, DTSS College of Commerce, J M Patel College of Commerce and Narsee Monjee College of Commerce And Economics. This workshop was organized in Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce on 29th August 2015 with IQAC of Rizvi College taking the leading role. \n\n> The workshop got an overwhelming response despite of being a holiday in most colleges due to Raksha Bandan. Teachers from all over the State from as far as Ratnagiri attended the workshop. More than one hundred and twenty five teachers and IQAC coordinators attended the workshop. \n\n> The program started with the welcome speech of Dr M Z Farooqui, Principal of Rizvi College of Arts, Science And Commerce. The objective of the program was given by Dr Kurhade, DTSS College of Commerce. The pre- lunch session was divided into two parts (i) A CAS presentation and (ii) guidelines for preparation of documents. The CAS presentation was given Shri. S B Mantri, Principal, Narsee Monjee College Commerce And Economics, who was also the Convenor of the Committee formed to draft the guidelines for CAS. The CAS presentation covered in details all the three categories of the API-PBAS form. The guidelines for preparation of documents for CAS were given by Mrs Yogini Ghare, Deputy Registrar and Dr. D.N.Sarkar, Principal, J M Patel College Commerce also was a Member of the Committee formed to draft the Guidelines for CAS. They explained how the papers should be prepared by the teachers and submitted for promotions under CAS. \n\n>The post lunch session was a question-answer session. The Joint Director Nominee, Dr Jagtap also joined the panel in this session. The panel consisted of the Principals of the four colleges, the deputy registrar and the JD nominee. More than sixty questions were taken in this session from the participating teachers. The Vote of thanks was given by Dr ( Mrs) Anjum Ara Ahmad, IQAC Coordenator of Rizvi College. All the participating professors were given formats and the procedures for filling the API- PBAS .The same and many other details given by the resource persons were emailed to them. \n\n>Dr Anjum Ara Ahmad \nVice-Principal And IQAC Coordinator]]></string>
    <string name="RD_string1">Rizvi College of Arts, Commerce and Science offers undergraduate courses in three streams: Arts, Science and Commerce; post-graduate course in Commerce and Ph.D in two subjects Botany and Commerce.</string>
    <string name="RD_String2"><![CDATA[\n> The Bachelor of Arts requires three years of full time study consisting of six semesters. The college offers six arts subjects: Urdu, Hindi, English, Philosophy, Sociology and Economics. Arts degrees are focused on increasing a students’ knowledge and critical thinking in accordance to the syllabus and curriculum prescribed by the University of Mumbai. These courses aim to prepare students with a sound knowledge and skills to connect across geographical, disciplinary, social and cultural boundaries, understand the importance of ethical behavior and lifelong learning habits. \n\n >Click on the following departmental links to download the program outcome/program specific outcome and course outcome of different arts departments:]]></string>
    <string name="RD_String3"><![CDATA[\n> The Bachelor of Science requires three years of full time study consisting of six semesters. The College offers six science subjects: Chemistry, Physics, Botany, Zoology, Computer Science and Information Technology. These courses introduce a wide range of topics to students, develop reasoning through unfamiliar problems through critical and analytical thinking and to find a systematic approach in analyzing solving problems through teamwork with importance to safe laboratory practice. The college also offers Ph.D in Botany. \n\n> Click on the following departmental links to download the program outcome/program specific outcome and course outcome of different arts departments:]]></string>
    <string name="RD_String4">Click on the following departmental links to download the program outcome/program specific outcome and course outcome of different arts departments:</string>
    <string name="RD_String5"><![CDATA[\n> The Bachelor of Commerce requires three Years of full time study consisting of six semesters. The college offers specialization course in Accountancy and Management. It aims to provide students with the knowledge, tools of analysis and skills to understand and participate in the modern business and economic world. The college also offers M.Com with specialization in Accountancy and Management.The college also offers Ph.D in Commerce. \n\n> Click on the following departmental links to download the program outcome/program specific outcome and course outcome of different arts departments:]]></string>
    <string name="ALEvents_String1"><![CDATA[>Alumni meet for the year 2016-17 was held on Saturday 18th February 2017 in the college auditorium. The invitation for the same was posted personally by the faculty and was spread through What’sApp and Face Book. The initiative received an overwhelming response from the alumni to the extent that the staff kept receiving calls for extending the dates of registration. \n\n> The meeting was attended by over 250 alumni of which 225 were registered alumnus and the rest were the invitees. Principal Dr. S.S Hussain and Vice Principal, Dr. Mrs Anjum Ara gave them a warm welcome and spoke in brief to them about the NAAC accreditation and the significant contribution of the alumnis for the same. \n\n> Many students took this as an opportunity to share their views about their journey as a student and their interaction with faculty and staff. Most of them were excited about meeting their friends and coming back to college. The alumnis were presented with premium pen with college’s name embossed on it. \n\n> The occasion was also graced with the presence of alumnis who are serving as the faculty i different sections of the college including Dr. Alkama Faqih from Botany Deptment, Prof. Huma Sayed of B.M.M Department and Shakiba Merchant of B.M.S department who managed the stage and did the comparing for the programme. \n\n> Mr. Aakash Bhardwaj, well know actor, Director, mucisian and an Event Manager ensured to take time out of his busy schedule to come back to his college and reunite with his friends and teachers. He also urged to involve the alumnis for betterment of students and college. \n\n> Most of the alumnis were positive about the met and suggested to increase them of meets in a year. They also appreciated the efforts of their teachers and mentors in grooming their personality and encouraging their self confidence. \n\n> Mariyah Gour-Ghori \n Convenor, Alumni Committee \n\n> redox admin \n Convenor, Alumni Committee\\]]></string>
    <string name="ALEvents_string2"><![CDATA[> Alumni Meet for the academic year 2015-16 was held on 29th Nov 2015 in the college auditorium from 5.00pm onwards. It had an overwhelming response from the ex-students who kept joining us even by 9.00pm. They had a busy schedule but did not want to miss meeting their teachers and buddies. There were series of performances on stage by our alumni who are now faculty at our own institute including Prof. Zakir, Prof. Shakiba Merchant. A large no. of ex- students from Dept. of Computer Science and I.T. also entertained the gathering with their performances. All the alumni were presented with mementos of the college. \n\n> The senior alumni of 1980\'s and the alumni who have brought laurels to the college through distinguished contribution into their respective field were felicitated. \n\n> Principal, Dr. M. Z. Farooqui welcomed the gathering and explained the significance of their contribution towards branding of college. He also highlighted the role of alumni in NAAC and academic audit. Many alumni showed their eagerness in coming back to college for imparting lectures and sharing their expertise in their field. \n\n> Later, Mr. Rehman Khan, the famous comedian and ex-student of the college entertained the gathering with his jokes. He also enlightened and guided the students to make their career into entertainment industry. \n\n> The programme was a great success with alumni showing their eagerness to contribute towards alumni activities that would further help the college. \n\n> Prof. Mariyah Gour Ghori \nConvenor, Alumni committee]]></string>
    <string name="ALEvents_String3"><![CDATA[> Alumni meet for the year 2014-15 was held on 23rd August 2014 at 5.00p.m. in the college auditorium. It had an overwhelming response with over 120 ex-students who grace the occassion with their presence. \n\n> Some eminent students like Shashank Shah, Rehman Khan and many others along with their batchmates reunited to remember the memories of their college days. Ms. Sonali entertained the audience with her exclusive stage performance. Mr. Rehman Khan made people roll with his unending jokes. \n\n> The Principal Dr. M. Z. Farooqui motivated and invited the alumni to be part of numerous activities of the college. \n\n> Dr. Anjum Ara along with Prof. MariyahGour-Ghori, convenor Alumni Association and many faculties including Dr. Ashfaque Khan, Prof. Shaikh Shahida, Dr. MadhulikaPathak, Prof. Nuzhat Farooqui and Prof. Pratima Sharma interacted with the alumni. \n\n> A page was created on the facebook Gems of Rizvites by the student council\'s General Secretary Ms. Naina Thorat and all were requested to be the part of the same.Yearly and lifetime membership was introduced and alumni were encouraged to be the part of the same. \n\n Prof.MariyahGour-Ghori Convenor, Alumni Association]]></string>
    <string name="Mphotos_string1">Mumbai Runs for a Cause \n\nThe Rizvi Group hosted its second mega Saquib Rizvi Memorial Cancer Awareness Marathon on Sunday, 2nd February 2020 from 6 a.m. to 9.30 a.m. on MMRDA Grounds, BKC, in collaboration with Help Yourself Foundation. \n\nThe initiative is driven by constant guidance and encouragement of the President,Shri. Mr.Akhtar Hasan Rizvi and Director,Adv. Mrs. Rubina Akhtar Hasan Rizvi of Rizvi Education Society.Saquib Rizvi Memorial Cancer Awareness Marathon, this year, witnessed more than 5000 participants running with a mission for a noble cause to create awareness and to raise fund for the cancer patients. \n\nThe marathon was supported by the Mumbai Police and had runners from different walks of life which also included cancer patients, the dignitaries and the celebrities running to support a noble cause. \n\nDep.High Commission and Head of Mission for People\'s Republic of Bangladesh H.E Mr.Md.Lutfor Rahman, Deputy Mayor of Mumbai, Mr. Suhas Wadkar, Asst.Commissioner of Police,IDCell Jammu and Kashmir,Mrs.Shahida Ganguly, Dr. Sufi Sayed, Ms Universal Peace and Harmony 2017, Peace Ambassador and Social Activist,Dr.Amjad Pathan were some of the dignitaries who were kind enough to take out time from Thier busy schedules for this noble cause.</string>
    <string name="AlumniSpeak_String1">Mr. Shashant Shah (Director, movies like Bhagate Raho, Chalo Delhi, Dosvadonia) is an alumnus of Rizvi College of Arts, Science and Commerce. Who completed his graduation in chemistry (B.Sc. chemistry) in 1994. \n\nI am proud of my college, which has retained the prestigious Guru Nanak Dev Trophy sponsored by Mumbai University for the overall supremacy it sports. \n\nWhen it comes to drama and street play WE ARE THE BEST!!!, I would like to request our college authorities to make our college festival “JASHN-E-RIZVI” (2 days) to say a week, which would mean more college participating, more events and a lot fun. \n\n Cheers and Hats off to Rizvi College Management / Trustees / Principal / Staff and students and wish you all the best for future God bless!!!</string>
    <string name="AlumniSpeak_String2">Seemab Amjad Khan, an alumnus of Rizvi College of Arts, Science and Commerce who is the assistant director of movies like Himmatwala (New) and Humshakals says, “I did my graduation in Commerce in the year 2003 and I am very much attached to my college and fondly remember the good old days particularly sports (cricket).”</string>
    <string name="AlumniSpeak_String3">Mr. Rehman Khan, an alumnus of Rizvi College of Arts / Science / Commerce passed out way back in 1996-97, is a famous stand up comedian, who has famous comedy series like Comedy Circus and PapadPol to his credit telecasted in the channel Sub TV. \n\n“I would like to congratulate the principal Dr. M. Z. Farooqui, teachers who are doing great job in developing the college in all direction and if any help is needed on my part I am always available.I feel honored to be Judge for such unique Amjad Khan award for street play in selecting the best actors/directors from colleges participating from all over Mumbai.</string>
    <string name="ContactUs_string">\nRizvi Educational Complex, \nOff. Carter Road, \nBandra (West), Mumbai 400050. \nMaharashtra. \n\n022-2648 0348 / 022-2600 4245 \n022-2649 7448 \n\nBUS Routes \nFrom Bandra Station (West) : 220 \nFrom Khar Station (West) : 220 \nFrom Kurla Station (West) : 304 \nFrom Versova: 56</string>
    <string-array name="Arts_spinner_list">
        <item>Please Select to Download</item>
        <item>Economics</item>
        <item>Sociology</item>
        <item>English</item>
        <item>Urdu</item>
        <item>Mass Media</item>
        <item>Hindi</item>
        <item>Philosophy</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="Science_spinner_list">
        <item>Please Select to Download</item>
        <item>Physics</item>
        <item>Botany</item>
        <item>Zoology</item>
        <item>Chemistry</item>
        <item>Mathematics</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="IT_spinner_list">
        <item>Please Select to Download</item>
        <item>Computer Science/IT</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="Commerce_spinner_list">
        <item>Please Select to Download</item>
        <item>Accountancy</item>
        <item>Business Law</item>
        <item>Commerce</item>
        <item>Foundation Course</item>
        <item>B.M.S</item>
        <item>B.Com(Finance)</item>
        <item>B.Com(Insurance)</item>
        <item>EVS</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>

