<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RIZVI</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="long_text">Press the download button to see the complete document.</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="msc_details">Rizvi college of Arts, Science and Commerce offers Programme of M.Sc by Research of University of Mumbai in the area of Chemistry.\n
\n\nThe course structure, eligibility and selection criteria is as per University of Mumbai norms. The coaching for course work and the doctoral thesis work is done at the Institute under the able guidance of the Ph.D. and M.Sc. guide Dr. Shamsul Hussain And Dr. Rajendra Chaudhary. The Institute offers excellent research facilities in terms of statistical packages, online databases, online journals, etc.
\n\nThe following students have enrolled for the M.Sc by Research program :-</string>
    <string name="Collaborations_title">MOUs / Collaborations with Institutions / Other universities / Industries / Corporate Entities:-</string>
    <string name="Collaborations">>> LOU with Bhartiya Vidyapeeth University IMED, Pune for Faculty Exchange Programme and Research Activities.
\n\n>> MOU - Visara Technologies Services LLP for GROW YOUR SKILL learning program for Final year students. Number of students registered 34.(2016-17)
\n\n>> “CREEDY” employability program conducted by Techno serve in collaboration with Citibank’s CSR initiative and British Council on “Skill Set Enhancement and Employability support for Youth in Urban Slums in Mumbai”. This 100 hrs program is free of cost. A Certificate on successful completion of Course was provided.
\n\n>> MOU was signed with AIM Institute of Management for short term courses under skill development program for one year diploma course in Marketing Management/Business Management/Dip in Accountancy and Book keeping Courses for Minority students only (127 students enrolled). Also around 80 students registered for Certificate course in Travel and Tourism. This course was also free of cost with scholarship of Rs 1450/- awarded upon completion of the course (2015-16).
\n\n>> TOI India (CSR Initiative) in collaboration with British Council tied up with Institute for imparting free short term courses in Communication And Soft Skill development program. (2016-17)
\n\n>> NSS unit signed an MOU with Anubhav Mumbai which is a non-profit or ganisation with a mission to work for Underprivileged, Youth and Women.
\n\n>> NSS unit of the College undertake Mega Medical Camp in collaboration with Lions Club of Oshiwara and Think Foundation every year.
\n\n>> NSS collaborated with TATA Memorial Hospital for Blood Donation.
\n\n>> NSS also collaborated with Zahan Foundation for holding Medical Camp for Teaching and Non – Teaching Staff of the college.
\n\n>> NSS Unit and Environment Committee collaborated with Stree Mukti Sanghatana (NGO) on Paper Recycling, E - Waste, Compost Pit and Green Audit.
\n\n>> WDC Department collaborated with Akshara, Population first and Ladli to organise various competitions, seminars and workshops on Gender Issues.</string>
    <string name="dpbotsetailstxt">he course structure, eligibility and selection criteria is as per University of Mumbai norms. The coaching for course work and the doctoral thesis work is done at the Institute under the able guidance of the Ph.D. guide Dr. Nitesh Joshi. The Institute offers excellent research facilities in terms of statistical packages, online databases, online journals, etc. \n\nThe current details of the Ph.D. program are as given below</string>
</resources>
