<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RIZVI</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="long_text">Press the download button to see the complete document.</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="Collaborations_title">MOUs / Collaborations with Institutions / Other universities / Industries / Corporate Entities:-</string>
    <string name="Collaborations">>> LOU with Bhartiya Vidyapeeth University IMED, Pune for Faculty Exchange Programme and Research Activities.\n\n>> MOU - Visara Technologies Services LLP for GROW YOUR SKILL learning program for Final year students. Number of students registered 34.(2016-17)\n\n>> “CREEDY” employability program conducted by Techno serve in collaboration with Citibank’s CSR initiative and British Council on “Skill Set Enhancement and Employability support for Youth in Urban Slums in Mumbai”. This 100 hrs program is free of cost. A Certificate on successful completion of Course was provided.\n\n>> MOU was signed with AIM Institute of Management for short term courses under skill development program for one year diploma course in Marketing Management/Business Management/Dip in Accountancy and Book keeping Courses for Minority students only (127 students enrolled). Also around 80 students registered for Certificate course in Travel and Tourism. This course was also free of cost with scholarship of Rs 1450/- awarded upon completion of the course (2015-16).\n\n>> TOI India (CSR Initiative) in collaboration with British Council tied up with Institute for imparting free short term courses in Communication And Soft Skill development program. (2016-17)\n\n>> NSS unit signed an MOU with Anubhav Mumbai which is a non-profit or ganisation with a mission to work for Underprivileged, Youth and Women.\n\n>> NSS unit of the College undertake Mega Medical Camp in collaboration with Lions Club of Oshiwara and Think Foundation every year.\n\n>> NSS collaborated with TATA Memorial Hospital for Blood Donation.\n\n>> NSS also collaborated with Zahan Foundation for holding Medical Camp for Teaching and Non – Teaching Staff of the college.\n\n>> NSS Unit and Environment Committee collaborated with Stree Mukti Sanghatana (NGO) on Paper Recycling, E - Waste, Compost Pit and Green Audit.\n\n>> WDC Department collaborated with Akshara, Population first and Ladli to organise various competitions, seminars and workshops on Gender Issues.</string>
    <string name="dpbotsetailstxt">he course structure, eligibility and selection criteria is as per University of Mumbai norms. The coaching for course work and the doctoral thesis work is done at the Institute under the able guidance of the Ph.D. guide Dr. Nitesh Joshi. The Institute offers excellent research facilities in terms of statistical packages, online databases, online journals, etc. \n\nThe current details of the Ph.D. program are as given below</string>
    <string name="Convocation_details">1) Convocation Ceremony 2020 on 29th February 2020 at 8:30 a.m\n\n2) Registration will be considered only after payment of fees at the office fees counter\n\n3) Registration Fees: Rs. 500/- (Rs. 400/- for Convocation and 100/- for Alumni registration) to be paid in cash at the Admin Office fees counter on the ground floor from 10:30 a.m. to 1:00 p.m. and 2:00 p.m. to 4:30 p.m.\n\n4) Please show the confirmation mail that you receive after filling the form, at the fees counter and pay the fees\n\n5) Please check your name in the list before Registration\n\n6) Last Date for Registration - 27th February, 2020\n\n7) Names of B.Sc.I.T. and B.Sc.C.S. students can be found in B.Sc. list\n\n8) Names of B.B.I. and B.A.F. students can be found in B.Com list\n\n9) Registration form link is given below</string>
    <string name="ncc_1string">N.C.C cadets of Rizvi College have regularlyand successfully participated in Physically and mentally highly demanding national level camps (competitions) like TSC (ThalSena Camp), RDC (Republic Day Camp) etc. Though this in itself an achievement, someendured to achieved greater goals.</string>
    <string name="ncc_2string">Sushant Sail, a second year cadet of Rizvi college was the sole cadet from Mumbai selected to Maharashtra Kabbaddi team in N.C.C National Games, Delhi in August 2015. The Maharashtra team won silver medal in the competition.</string>
    <string name="Ncc_title_string">Individual Achievements of N.C.C Cadets (June 2015 - August 2016)</string>
    <string name="ncc_3string">TusharTavandkar, a third year cadet and S.Y.B.COM student of Rizvi College, competed with the cadets of 01.Maharashtra.Battalion and won gold medal in obstacle race at ThalSena Camp (TSC), Nashik in July 2016. He was selected through thetraining and elimination rounds of the first three camps of the series of back to back camps (each of 12 days duration) that leads to prestigious national level competition in Delhi in the September, 2016.</string>
    <string name="ncc_4string">Khan Kaif, a second year cadet and S.Y.J.C. science student of Rizvi College, at the time of writing this article, has already made it through the training and elimination rounds of the first five camps and is currently being trained in the sixth camp of the series of camps that cumulates to competing in the prestigious national level competition in Delhi in September, 2016.</string>
    <string name="Assocation">\n> WOMEN’S DEVELOPMENT CELL: It is a special cell to inculcate self-reliance, boldness and confidence in girl students, so that, they can march shoulder to shoulder with their male counter parts.
\n\n> DLLE: The Department of Lifelong Learning and Extension has been recognized as a department to promote meaningful and sustained rapport between colleges and communities.
\n\n> ALUMNI ASSOCIATION: The ex-student Association has been set up to provide a platform for mutual inter-face among the past and present students of the college. To utilize the expertise and experiences of the ex-students for the upliftment of the performance of the College and to guide the present students to achieve their goals in a better way.
\n\n> NATIONAL CADET CORPS (NCC): The College has been allowed to raise a NCC unit for boys attached to the 01 st Maharashtra Battalion NCC Army Wing. It has a strength of One Part-Time Commissioned Officer and 60 Cadets. The NCC training imparted to the cadets during regular parades which are held on Sundays and in the various camps held during the year. The Cadets are prepared for the "B" and "C" certificate examinations. Students who desire to enroll for the NCC should contact the NCC officer.
\n\n> NATIONAL SOCIAL SERVICE (NSS):To encourage students to play a larger and more active role in the society, the college provides the NSS scheme at both the Degree and Junior College level. Students who desire to join the scheme should contact the NSS officer. This extra• institutional service is available free-of-charge to the students.
\n\n> STUDENT’S GRIEVANCE CELL:It has been set up to create a harmonious environment by redressing the grievances of the students concerned with academic and other related matters.
\n\n> CAREER GUIDANCE AND PLACEMENT CELL: It provides an opportunity to students to seek new openings after completing their College education and help them in moulding their career and placement.
\n\n> STUDENT’S COUNSELING CELL:Counseling is done by professionals who look after the welfare of the students by helping them to cope with stress and developing confidence among them to overcome and face highs and lows of the life.
\n\n> STUDENT’S1 COUNCIL:It consists of student representatives who look after and promote the productive involvement of the students in the day to day activities of the college.
\n\n> Mahila Takrar Nivaran Samiti This cell was constituted by State Government, and made mandatory in all organizations, public as well as private sector, when there was a demanding need to protect women folk against crime done to them in work-place.</string>
    <string name="ncc_string5">Care-taker office of N.C.C Unit, Rizvi College, would like to thank respected Principal, Dr. M. Z. Farooqui and Vice-Principal,Dr.AnjumAra for supporting and encouraging N.C.C, Ex. A.N.O Ashok Singh for guidance post retirement from N.C.C.\n\nAll the efforts, support, encouragement and guidance put in by the college will eventually be of no significance without the spirited, diligent and persistent efforts put in by the cadets of our N.C.C. unit. They rightfully deserve the greatest appreciation.\n\nThank You.</string>
</resources>

